Guide to the Cornell University Press and Comstock Publishing Company records, [ca. 1880-1935]
Cornell University Press and Comstock Publishing Company records, [ca. 1880-1935]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Press and Comstock Publishing Company records, [ca. 1880-1935]
35-6-257
Cornell University Press.
9.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, manuscripts, proofs, and illustrative material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, manuscripts, proofs, and illustrative material pertaining to books published by the Cornell University Press and the Comstock Publishing Company; correspondence pertaining to a merger of the Nature Study Review and Nature Magazine; and correspondence pertaining to John W. ("Uncle John") Spencer's stories and letters for children on nature study and rural life; correspondents include Anna Botsford Comstock, Mary Eleanor Davis, Paul S. Galtsoff, Albert H. Hartzell, Frank E. Lutz, James G. Needham, Arthur Newton Pack, Cuthbert W. Pound, Percival S. Ridsdale, John W. Spencer, and Paul S. Welch.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, manuscripts, proofs, and illustrative material pertaining to books published by the Cornell University Press and the Comstock Publishing Company; correspondence pertaining to a merger of the Nature Study Review and Nature Magazine; and correspondence pertaining to John W. ("Uncle John") Spencer's stories and letters for children on nature study and rural life; correspondents include Anna Botsford Comstock, Mary Eleanor Davis, Paul S. Galtsoff, Albert H. Hartzell, Frank E. Lutz, James G. Needham, Arthur Newton Pack, Cuthbert W. Pound, Percival S. Ridsdale, John W. Spencer, and Paul S. Welch.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University Press.; Comstock, Anna Botsford, 1854-1930.; Davis, Mary Eleanor, 1910-1968.; Galtsoff, Paul Simon, 1887-; Hartzell, Albert H.; Lutz, Frank Eugene, 1879-1943.; Needham, James G. (James George), 1868-1956.; Pack, Arthur Newton, 1893-; Pound, Cuthbert Winfred, 1864-1935.; Ridsdale, Percival Sheldon.; Spencer, John W.; Welch, Paul Smith, 1882-; Comstock Publishing Company.
Titles:
Nature study review.; Nature magazine.
Subjects:
University presses--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Publishers and publishing--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Natural history--Study and teaching.; Natural history literature.; Nature stories.; Country life.; Children--Books and reading.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Compendium correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Compendium abstracts (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Compendium page proofs (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Compendium odds and ends (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Compendium galley proofs (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Illustrations (Box 1, Folder 6)
- List of addresses on 3x5 cards (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Comstock photos, 1932-1933 (S-T) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Original proof of Fig. 31 of Culture Methods (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Proofs of "Wings of Insects" (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Proofs, pictures, etc. of Hahn, Applied Biochemistry (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Letter concerning "Organized Play" (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Acknowledgments to Comstock's Introduction to Entomology ( Dec. 10, 1924 ) [Transferred to Boxes 10-12] (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Picture proofs for Sweetman: Biological Control of Insects (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Carbon copy of An Introduction to Entomology, Part I (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Copy of An Introduction to Entomology, Ch. 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Table of contents for An Introduction to Entomology (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Ch. 4, An Introduction to Entomology (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Table of figures, An Introduction to Entomology (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Illustrations for An Introduction to Entomology (Box 3, Folder 9)
- "Wings of Spidoptera" (Box 3, Folder 10)
- "Wing of Diptera) (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Box of negatives on glass from the McMillan Co. to Prof. Comstock (Box 3, Folder 12)
- "Duplicate prints" negatives on glass (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Personal negatives of photographs, on glass (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Engraved steel plate--flower (Box 3, Folder 15)
- "Wings of Lepidoptera" (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Reprint from Fortune--The Univ. of Chicago, Hutchinson's "new look" (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Clippings from a publisher's journal (Box 3, Folder 18)
- History of Sage House in Ithaca Journal, 2013-11-23 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous illustrations (Box 4)
- Practical Course in Touch Typing (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Illustrations (for An Introduction to Entomology?) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- First copy, An Introduction to Entomology (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Proofs of figures, An Introduction to Entomology (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Illustrations (for An Introduction to Entomology) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Resolutions of the faculty of the New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell upon the retirement of Anna Comstock (Box 5, Folder 6)
- "The Wings," first draft for An Introduction to Entomology (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Copy, An Introduction to Entomology, ch. 3 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Legends for figures, An Introduction to Entomology (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Illustrations (for An Introduction to Entomology) (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Original drawings for figures, An Introduction to Entomology, Pt. II (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Duplicate prints, spiders (Box 5, Folder 12)
- An Introduction to Entomology, draft, ch. 4 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Original drawings for the illustrations, An Introduction to Entomology, Pt. I (Box 5, Folder 14)
- List of legends (for An Introduction to Entomology?) (Box 5, Folder 15)
- First copy, An Introduction to Entomology, ch. 2 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Illustrations (for An Introduction to Entomology?) (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Lore of an Adirondack County by E. F. Cutting, galley proofs (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Proof of Islandica, Vol. 26 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- The Canadian Entomologist, Vol. 57, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Cut of T. O. Howard (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Proof of figures for Cortner: Selected Topics in Colloidal Chemistry (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Revision of Handbook (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Manuscript of The Spider Book (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Biological Control of Insects, proof (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Proof, H. J. Davenport: Economics of Alfred Marshall (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Hahn: Applied Radiochemistry, proof (Box 6, Folder 9)
- "Poor Collin's Proof, Ainsworth" (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Pauling's manuscript: "Nature of the Chemical Bond" (Box 7, Folder 1-15)
- American Bird Songs, 1942; SR-31428-31433 (Box 7)
  Six 30cm 78 rpm discs.
  Kellogg, P.P.; Allen, A.A.
- An Introduction to Entomology, Pt. II, first copy (Box 8)
- Proofs of Engravings for "Daniel's Book" (Box 9)
- Three 4" boxes of letters, one dated, two undated: Comstock correspondence concerning "Nature" magazine; "Uncle John" letters; Jack and Jill stories for publication in monthly Grange Review (Box 10-12)
- Wooden cases of slides (Box 13-21)